Yes, I'm fine.
I'm eating properly.
No, you don't have to.
I bet you're too busy for that anyway.
Yeah, I thought so.
You're too far.
Snow?
No, of course it's not snowing here.
Ok, bye then.
Father
Mute
Keypad
Speakers
Add
Video Call
Contacts
End Call
Father
Mute
Keypad
Speakers
Add
Video Call
Contacts
End Call
Father
Mute
Keypad
Speakers
Add
Video Call
Contacts
End Call
Ending Call...
Father
Mute
Keypad
Speakers
Add
Video Call
Contacts
End Call
Father
Ending Call...
Mute
Keypad
Speakers
Add
Video Call
Contacts
End Call
Call Ended
My Friend
Sora no
Method
negaigoto yureru oto sotto hisomeru
Snow falls gently past my face,
hoho no soba de mau yukitachi
and my fears and hopes are forgotten.
takusan no koukai kako wo musubu egaotachi
Your smile takes away all of my past regrets,
kitakaze no sasayaki kurete torokeru
kitakaze no sasayaki kurete tokeru
and they melt into the arcadian north wind.
fuyuzora no samishisa wo kasanete
I'll embrace the emptiness I feel on this wintery night
yasashisa no hitomi koete
and look into your gentle eyes.
ima tsutaetai melody
This melody I'll share with you now
yubisashita ichibanboshi hikaru sora ni
is like the light of a single star shining in the sky,
kakiatsumeta mirai kajikanda yubi no sukima tooru seiza tachi
Keep holding onto your destiny so it won't slip through your numb fingers.
aa kono basho kara mita keshiki kanaetai
Oh, how I wish I could make this view come true.
yakusoku ne
I promise you one day I will.
The Memory's Whereabouts
In first place!
Offertory Chest
That didn't take you guys very long.
But of course!
You're the second ones here, though.
What? No way!
Who was it?
Who could've possibly beaten us here?
Let's see...
Mizusaka's team.
Oh, your twin brother.
Quick, Sensei!
I need that stamp!
Our team needs to make progress too!
Offertory Chest
There's four members in your team, isn't there?
Let's wait for the rest.
What...
Koharu! You're too slow!
There's no need to hurry...
Offertory Chest
Of course there is! This is war!
We have to win!
Orienteering is a little bit different from war...
Don't take orienteering lightly!
Speaking of which,
where are the other two?
Nonoka's...
What are you doing back there?!
I'm waiting for Togawa-san to catch up!
C'mon guys!
Offertory Chest
Don't you want to win?
As long as we all have fun, it'll be okay.
Nonoka!
You're our group's leader!
Get Shione over here!
This is stupid.
Sweet! That's the third one down.
Um, the next one is...
Oh, I know where this is.
This is behind the hotel near my house.
Yes, that's right!
I think our shop is one of the checkpoints, too.
My parents were talking about it with the teachers the other day.
Orienteering
Booklet
Um...
Okay! Time to get going!
Orienteering
Booklet
Yuzuki, you're going to wear yourself out at this rate.
Orienteering
Booklet
Aren't we cheating a little here?
It's just a home-field advantage!
We've had to share our hometown with that stupid Disc for ages!
We deserve to have a slight lead!
"Deserve...?"
And besides,
their group has the same advantage!
What are you talking about?
We're not gonna lose to you, got it?!
Is she up to no good again?
Sorry, I'm not supposed to fraternize with the enemy. Excuse me.
Excuse us.
Hey, aren't you guys forgetting about this checkpoint?
We were going to leave that one for last, okay?!
Target in sight!
Lemme go stamp us off!
I am the leader, right?
Don't let that bother you.
It's important for a leader to take advantage of an eager volunteer.
Kiryuu Hot Spring
Is that so?
Thanks, Koharu.
Motorboats
Maybe I'm imagining things...
Nope. She's definitely avoiding me.
Did something happen between you and Shione?
Nothing comes to mind...
Kiryuu Hot Spring
C'mon guys, quit being so slow!
Let's keep moving!
Kiryuu Hot Spring
We gotta hurry to the next checkpoint!
We're hot on the enemy's heels!
How far was it to your house again, Koharu?
Well, you've been there before, haven't you?
This is what happens when you don't pace yourself.
Oh, heavenly maiden!
It's all that thing's fault!
My lifeforce is being drained away!
It's got to be some...
mysterious, invisible power!
Sounds like you still have energy to spare.
My point is...
It's not my fault!
I'm blaming that Disc for everything!
Right.
Um...
Could I talk to you?
Togawa-san...
Shione-san!
I heard you the first time.
Oh, good.
What?
Do you need something?
U-Um, not exactly...
It's just that, um, I haven't really had
the chance to talk with you yet, and...
When we met here for the first time,
why did you say what you did?
Why did you come back
here after all this time?
How irritating.
U-Um, Shione-san!
If you call out to me again
like we're actually friends,
Huh?
If you ever do it again...
Wh-What?
I'll slap you.
Why?
Are you all right?
Yeah.
You shouldn't blame yourself.
Shione...
She was never very friendly towards other people.
She's changed a lot from when she was little.
Have you known her for a long time?
Yes. Shione grew up in this town, too.
Come on guys! What's the holdup?
All right then...
I'm not going to accept being shunned for no reason.
Koharu, thanks for looking out for me.
I think I still want to be Shione-san's friend,
so I'll go talk to her again.
Sure. Good luck.
Shiihara
Store
Kiriyako
Shore
Um, Togawa-san.
I heard that you've lived here since you were young.
The truth is I used to live here too.
Well, I was really little,
so I don't remember much about it.
So I was right.
Huh?
Shione... san?
Nonoka.
Y-Yes?
You're annoying.
Go away.
I don't want to see you ever again.
Also, remember what I said?
Wh-What happened?
It's nothing.
Don't worry about it.
If you say so...
We're finally here!
I'll go and let the teacher know.
Oh, sure.
Thanks!
Sensei!
Quickly! Stamp us off!
Noel?
What are you doing?
Nonoka!
Noel!
Oh dear.
Mr. Monster, I'm so sorry!
Noel, are you hurt?
Here, wipe your face.
Nonoka!
Noel...
Nonoka, you're done with school already?
No, we're having extracurricular activities.
Ex... tra?
It means I'm still in school. Sorry.
Okay...
You're so cute!
Who's this?
Your little sister?
Would you mind if I kidnapped her?
I've mentioned her before, haven't I?
This is Noel.
Good to meet'cha!
Noel!
Nice to meet you.
Who's that?
Shione, we're moving to the next checkpoint.
What?
Why are you being so cold to Nonoka?
Because I don't like her.
That's all there is to it.
You haven't figured it out yet?
I don't blame you.
No one would expect her
to come back, now of all times.
Eh?
Enemy sighted!
Shiihara
Store
Kiriyako
Shore
Don't think you're too far ahead!
We're a team of five now!
Why'd they get another member?
Dunno.
Come, Noel.
We'll show you what we're made of!
Hey, new girl.
Must be tough with such
a troublemaker on your team.
What do you mean?
No, not at all.
I'm saying that she's mocking us.
Shiihara
Store
Kiriyako
Shore
Hurry up! Hurry up! Hurry up!
Orienteering
Booklet
Our next checkpoint is on the
other side of those mountains.
Orienteering
Booklet
Is the next one our last stop?
Yup, it should be.
There's still a bit to go, though.
Noel, aren't you tired?
Noel's not tired!
You look the most exhausted to me, Yuzuki.
I'm not tired at all!
Huh? Where's Togawa-san?
She was walking behind us not too long ago...
Maybe she got lost somewhere back there?
She's probably just lagging behind.
Orienteering
Booklet
I'm gonna go look for her!
Orienteering
Booklet
Huh?
Orienteering
Booklet
I'll catch up to you guys!
Orienteering
Booklet
Nonoka?
Orienteering
Booklet
Shouldn't we all go?
Nonoka!
Noel will come too!
It's fine! I'll be back soon!
Wait there with everyone else!
Orienteering
Booklet
Yuzuki! Look after Noel for me!
Orienteering
Booklet
R-Right, got it!
Orienteering
Booklet
Is Nonoka going to be all right?
She's been gone for a while.
What are you doing?
Shione!
Where's Nonoka?
No idea.
Wait, how did you get in front of us?
Did she make a wrong turn somewhere?
I guess so.
Nonoka!
Noel, wait!
Noel-chan?
Togawa-san!
I think I got lost instead...
Noel!
Nonoka!
Yuzuki?
Souta-kun...
What?
We were done ages ago.
Right.
Koharu, we're in charge of
watching out for the stragglers.
Where's the new girl and the little kid?
Well...
Kiriyako Kindergarten
I didn't know this was here.
I wonder if they found Shione-san...
I can't seem to do anything right.
Komiya!
Nonoka!
Still, it's been a while since
we were all together like this.
Huh?
Oh, yeah, you're right.
We were all in different classes until last year.
Well, there's no way they'd let
both twins be in the same class.
It'd be too troublesome to deal with.
Hey, do you remember?
Back then, we—
Stop!
If she hadn't said that back then...
That Disc wouldn't be here today?
Of course not!
And you hate her for it?
Of course I do!
I hate that girl who called forth the Disc!
Then why are you friends with her?
Huh?
Kiriyako Kindergarten
Found you.
That tune...
I got really good, didn't I?
You're really...
Seven years ago...
Hm?
I wonder how far away Tokyo is...
There you are!
Oh?
What's up?
She told me to go find you
before it gets eaten...
Someone will eat it?
Yeah. Hurry!
Shiihara Store
Hot Spring Buns
There's one left, right?
So why can't I have it?
No, you can't!
It's one per person!
Hey!
Here, catch!
Wolf it down, quick!
Nice!
That's the end of that!
Aw, come on...
Huh?
Um, um...
Disc-san?
You told me about it before, right?
If you wish with all your friends together,
a Disc will appear.
Yeah, it was in a book I read.
Let's try it, together!
Huh?
I want to do something... with everyone.
Why?
We might not get to see
each other when it's winter...
You're right!
It'll be hard for us to meet up here when it's snowing too heavily.
Huh?
Yeah.
Then, before that happens...
Yup!
Nonoka's the same girl as back then?
That can't be true!
And why not?
Because Nonoka's my friend,
and she helped me with chasing away the Disc,
and...
And?
She used to live here.
Huh?
She said so herself.
Really?
She got all of us to help her summon the Disc,
and just disappeared from this town.
Unable to tell anyone, we've been silently regretting it these seven years, thinking,
"why did we do such a thing?"
And then she comes back and becomes your friend?
That says to me that she's here to mock us.
But...
But we don't know for sure
whether that was Nonoka or not!
Yuzuki...
Hey,
there she is.
I remember now.
I was the one who said it to everyone.
"Let's call it together."
Yup.
Nonoka, you called Noel.
Because...
I'm the Disc.
yureru minamo sono fukaku ni
The azure sky is as vast as the sea
aoi uchuu utsuttetane
forever reflected by the waves.
mirai soshite mata chitteyuku kisetsu oboeteiru
Don't you realize our futures are changing with the seasons?
watashitachi wa unmei tsumugi nagara
We merely pave the paths leading to our fates,
sono ito ga doko made
unaware of how far those strings
tsuzuiteku no ka shiranai mama de
would continue to be entwined.
tada soko ni
But...
inspiration yorokobi toka kotoba wo wakachiau tabi
These words that we share bring me joy and life,
aa itsuka owari no hi ga kuru sou kanji saseru yo
but still I know these days must come to an end.
initializer no tobira wo akeru toki ga kuru no darou
One day, I'll have to open the door to truly start my life.
kirei na toki wo tojikomete
I'll shut all those cheerful times behind me,
mizuumi ni shizumeta no
and bury them in a place I'll never reach again,
and bury them in a place I'll never reach again.
dakedo watashi heiki dayo to
but I tell myself that it'll all be okay
hoshi no tayori ni tsuzuru
if I have these stars here to guide me.
Next time, on Sora no Method:
"Fragments of Memories."
Look forward to it!
Fragments of Memories