You're here to grant my wish?
Yup!
Noel,
seven years ago...
Yes?
No, I just—
Nonoka?!
It can't be, can it?
Here you go, Nonoka!
Thank you, Noel.
Sora no
Method
negaigoto yureru oto sotto hisomeru
Snow falls gently past my face,
hoho no soba de mau yukitachi
and my fears and hopes are forgotten.
takusan no koukai kako wo musubu egaotachi
Your smile takes away all of my past regrets,
kitakaze no sasayaki kurete tokeru
and they melt into the arcadian north wind.
fuyuzora no samishisa wo kasanete
I'll embrace the emptiness I feel on this wintery night
yasashisa no hitomi koete
and look into your gentle eyes.
ima tsutaetai melody
This melody I'll share with you now
yubisashita ichibanboshi hikaru sora ni
is like the light of a single star shining in the sky,
kakiatsumeta mirai kajikanda yubi no sukima tooru seiza tachi
Keep holding onto your destiny so it won't slip through your numb fingers.
aa kono basho kara mita keshiki kanaetai
Oh, how I wish I could make this view come true.
yakusoku ne
I promise you one day I will.
The Pair's Promise
The weather's nice...
Good morning, Dad.
Mornin'.
Are two eggs okay with you?
Yeah.
Prospects on Increasing Budgets for Disc Supervision
Moving on to our next story.
Sunny-side up?
Prospects on Increasing Budgets for Disc Supervision
The Disc Supervision Budget for the
following fiscal year was discussed at...
Whatever you want.
Should you still be in your pajamas?
Speak for yourself, Dad.
Well, it's fine as long as you make it on time.
In time for what?
School.
Huh?
The opening ceremony's today, isn't it?
What?
But it's only August—
Yeah, I guess it's earlier
than the schools in Tokyo.
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
Well, it's the same as when you went to
elementary school here, so I figured you'd know.
I can't remember something from that long ago!
Toast the bread for me!
Sure thing.
Dad,
you moron!
I'm Komiya Nonoka.
Pleased to meet all of you.
Maybe you should try smiling a bit more.
Those eggs are probably overcooked now.
Hey, you were the one
who let me decide!
Take care on the way, okay?
See you later!
Nonoka!
Noel!
I came to see you.
Sorry, Noel! I'm in a hurry!
It's all my Dad's fault!
See you again later!
Bye.
Welcome.
Did you find the girl you were looking for?
Oh, so you weren't a tourist.
No, but it hasn't been
very long since I moved here.
Do you know which class
you're going to be in?
No, not yet.
There aren't many people from this town who go to our school.
Really?
Yup.
It'd be lovely if we're in the same class.
Yes, it would.
Kitami
Middle
School
Kitami
Middle
School
I'm Komiya Nonoka.
Pleased to meet all of you.
Komiya
Nonoka
Okay, class, let's all be sure
to make her feel welcome.
Komiya
Nonoka
You'll be sitting at the end
of row two, Komiya-san.
Um...
Um!
Don't you dare touch me.
You could have just answered if you'd heard me.
Why should I?
Huh?
We met before by the lake, didn't we?
And?
I was curious why you said that to me.
I wonder if there's anything fun to do.
When will Nonoka be back?
Komiya-san, let's go home together.
You can just call me Nonoka.
Just Koharu is fine for me, too.
Is your house near the lake?
Yup.
It's closer to the mountains though, so it's a little far to the lake.
This mornin—
Hold it!
Um...
That's Mizusaka Yuzuki.
You!
Is what you said true?
Huh?
I asked, did you really move to Kiriyako?
Yes... I did.
Come with me.
Huh?
W-Wait!
Just come on!
Wait a second, Mizusaka-san!
What do you want with me?
Tell me exactly how you feel.
Feel about what?
What else?
Do you like it?
Huh?
Or don't you?!
I'm talking about the Disc!
Hey, could we get two ginger ales, please?
You don't mind having the same thing, do you?
No...
I don't really mind.
Er... so where were we?
There's more?
Of course there is!
It's a big deal, okay?!
Calm down, please?
I don't know if you're aware,
but it was a huge issue seven years back.
It was on the news, so I know a little bit.
Also, right about then I was—
It's not the same unless you were actually here!
The Disc appeared out of nowhere
and it's just stayed above the lake since then,
but no one seems to care at all now!
All right, I hear you.
Sit down. Our drinks are here.
And besides, because of that Disc—
You can have mine too!
The rest of the townspeople don't seem to mind, though.
They're all being fooled.
By whom?
By the Disc!
Isn't that obvious?!
It's just been sitting there for the past seven years,
but we don't know what it could be hiding!
The safety of this town is being
jeopardized day after day!
We have to do something before it's too late!
This town seems to be the epitome of safe, though...
Who are you siding with exactly, Nonoka?
Your friend who needs your help, or that Disc?!
Well, my friend who needs my help, I guess.
Then it's settled!
We'll bring back peace to this town!
Just the two of us!
NO MORE DISC
We need your help!
Please help...
NO MORE DISC
Let's take back our town!
Disc           Palace
Shiihara Store
NO MORE DISC
...take back our town.
Please help!
Please help out!
Come on, you too, Nonoka.
Don't call out my name!
You've gotta be louder!
Otherwise, no one will hear you.
No, I meant—
Oh, I know!
Disc           Palace
Shiihara Store
NO MORE DISC
Wanna use this?
No thanks!
I'll be fine.
You sure?
Please help us!
Shiihara
Store
Kiriyako
Shore
Let's drive that Disc away from our town!
We have no need for that Disc in our town!
We mustn't slow down
in our efforts to drive it away!
Mizusaka-san!
What's up?
Oh, sorry.
How much longer are we going to be doing this?
Until the Disc goes away.
Are you serious?
'Course I am!
It'll be a piece of cake with everyone's support!
Koharu...
What are you doing,
dear customers?
No more
Disc!
NO MORE DISC
This is, um...
Right?
NO MORE DISC
We're, uh, doing our civic duty...
I think we should apologize!
Time for plan B!
B?
Why'd you run away?
Because!
We didn't do anything wrong.
Then we should have just explained to her...
Fat chance.
I've known her for too long.
I know exactly how she'd react.
Thanks, Nonoka.
Huh?
Thanks for coming here with me.
Well, things just turned out this way.
Still! It made me feel happy,
so thanks for that.
Sure...
Ok! Time for plan C!
There's a C?
Disc Supervison Department
Thanks for waiting.
Do you have an inquiry about the Disc?
Yes!
In that case, could you please fill out this form?
take effect immediately.
Seal
(Signature)
4. In the case of violations of regulations specified by Article 3 regarding Disc supervision, penalties will
3. What is written above is a helpful and constructive suggestion.
2. All written information and locations are relevant to the Disc above Kiriyako Town of Kitami City.
1. You are either a resident, corporate body, or organization in Kiriyako Town of Kitami City.
Your submission will be rejected without your signature.
Please sign below to confirm that you have fully read and understood the following terms.
4. Since the appearance of the Disc, you have felt psychological changes.
3. You have made previous visits about matters regarding the Disc.
2. Someone related to you has been affected by the Disc in some way.
1. You are requesting reparations.
(Fill this out only if you have selected purpose #1.)
Please select from the following. (Can choose multiple.)
Include any other specifics about your suggestion here:
Write any previous history you have with the Disc. Be specific:
Write in detail about your purpose of visit:
3. Other suggestions or thoughts pertaining to the Disc.
2. You wish to have an event or tourist attraction that includes the Disc.
1. You have an opinion or complaint in regards to the Disc.
Please select the closest to your purpose of visit from the following:
Address
Name
F
M
D.O.B.
YY      MM      DD
YY     MM     DD
Kiriyako Town Hall
Disc Supervision Department
Disc Inquiry Submission
Thanks, but I'd prefer to speak directly to whoever's in charge.
Who's the boss around here? I want to—
We're so sorry!
Never mind!
Let go of me, Nonoka!
Disc Supervison Department
I have to speak with the boss!
The boss!
Disc Supervison Department
Lemme see the boss!
Why'd you stop me?
You wouldn't have been able to speak to them anyway.
You can't say that for sure.
We used to be able to go on cruises to that island in the past, you know,
but since then, it's been closed off because it's "too dangerous".
That doesn't make any sense to me.
I won't accept how things are right now.
We have to take back our town.
Our daily lives are in danger!
Take back our lake!
Let's protect Kiriyako Town!
Strange Weather
NO MORE
DISC!
Sorry she's such a bother for you.
Don't be mad at Yuzuki.
I understand how she feels.
Parking Lot Directory
Where'd I put it?
What are you looking for?
A weapon.
Sweet Corn
One
Nonoka!
I finally found it!
Righty, we're all set!
What do you think you're doing?
Why should I tell you?
Sorry for intruding.
Mind telling me what that's about?
That's none of your business either.
Stop going around making things
difficult for other people.
I bet it's something stupid anyway.
It's not stupid.
Why do you insist on keeping this up?
"Why?"
I knew it.
Yuzuki?
I knew it!
Everything is the Disc and that girl's fault!
What's up with her?
Um...
Sorry for bothering you!
Wait, new girl.
Maybe it's better you don't.
Souta, you idiot!
Stupid Souta!
Stupid, stupid...
What are you doing?
Resorting to drastic measures.
I'm going to get to that island.
You can't!
That's too—
Unless I do this,
I won't be able to change anything.
Take my backpack.
Let's go, Nonoka.
Fine. I'll just go by myself.
I've been alone this whole time, anyway.
Mizusaka-san!
You're angry, aren't you?
No, not really.
I'm sorry.
Can I ask you something?
Yeah.
Why do you want to get rid of the Disc so badly?
There are some things that changed
when the Disc appeared seven years ago.
Some things that haven't changed back even now.
During the summer festival,
fireworks were lit above the lake.
Fireworks?
It wasn't a massive display or anything,
but the sight of the fireworks reflected on the water's surface was beautiful.
But now...
they don't do them anymore.
Let's fire it.
This flies, right?
Let's fire the rocket.
Sure.
Three, two, one!
Go!
It hardly got anywhere.
Yuzuki.
I'll help you.
Let's do something about that Disc together.
Will you really?
Yup.
As long as it's safe, of course.
Really?
Really.
We'll need to find more people to help us.
Nonoka.
Thanks.
It's pretty!
I wish Dad had come, too.
Yes, he should have.
Nonoka, have you been keeping
that promise you made with me?
Yup, I have!
Of course! That's my baby girl.
Mom, I...
Nonoka.
Nonoka, what's wrong?
Are you feeling bad?
Noel.
What's bothering you?
Is it something Noel can help you with?
Will you help us too, Noel?
Count me in!
What do you want Noel to do?
We're trying to get rid of the Disc from this town.
Nonoka, you don't like the Disc?
It's not that, but I want to
do something to help my friend.
Okay then.
Just wait a little bit, okay?
Great!
This makes three of us now.
yureru minamo sono fukaku ni
The azure sky is as vast as the sea
aoi uchuu utsuttetane
forever reflected by the waves.
mirai soshite mata chitteyuku kisetsu oboeteiru
Don't you realize our futures are changing with the seasons?
watashitachi wa unmei tsumugi nagara
We merely pave the paths leading to our fates,
sono ito ga doko made
unaware of how far those strings
tsuzuiteku no ka shiranai mama de
would continue to be entwined.
tada soko ni
But...
inspiration yorokobi toka kotoba wo wakachiau tabi
These words that we share bring me joy and life,
aa itsuka owari no hi ga kuru sou kanji saseru yo
but still I know these days must come to an end.
initializer no tobira wo akeru toki ga kuru no darou
One day, I'll have to open the door to truly start my life.
kirei na toki wo tojikomete
I'll shut all those cheerful times behind me,
mizuumi ni shizumeta no
and bury them in a place I'll never reach again,
and bury them in a place I'll never reach again.
dakedo watashi heiki dayo to
but I tell myself that it'll all be okay
hoshi no tayori ni tsuzuru
if I have these stars here to guide me.
Next time, on Sora no Method:
"The Memory's Whereabouts."
Look forward to it!
The Memory's Whereabouts